<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Maxime Chemin</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Maxime Chemin</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Publish using GitHub Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/obsidian-publish-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/obsidian-publish-github-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my video about &lt;a href=&#34;https://arkalim.org/blog/aws-saa-certification/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I cleared the AWS SAA Certification Exam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I shared my preparation strategy as well as tips to ace the exam. I also gave a glimpse of my revision notes that I prepared while taking the course and practice exams on Udemy. After that video was out, I got so many comments and DMs, requesting me to share my notes, but the problem was that I took these notes using a note-taking app called Obsidian which stores them in markdown format locally on my Mac. Once I&amp;rsquo;m done editing my notes, I push them to a GitHub repository to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t lose them if my laptop breaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kindle to Notion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/kindle-to-notion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/kindle-to-notion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;-githubhttpsgithubcomarkalimkindle-to-notion&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arkalim/kindle-to-notion&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like reading personal improvement and mindset change type books on &lt;strong&gt;Kindle&lt;/strong&gt; e-reader. Some of these books are downloaded straight from the internet and not from the Kindle store. I take highlights during my reading which I wanted to sync to my Notion workspace. There was no existing app that could do this job, so I developed my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kindle exports the highlights as a file named &lt;code&gt;MyClippings.txt&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;NodeJS&lt;/strong&gt; application reads the &lt;code&gt;MyClipping.txt&lt;/code&gt; file exported by Kindle, parses it using Regex, extracts all the highlights, book names, highlight time etc and creates a JSON. It then uses &lt;strong&gt;Notion API&lt;/strong&gt; to sync these highlights to a database in my Notion workspace. The app maintains a cache (JSON) containing the number of highlights synced for each book. This allows the highlights to be synced incrementally, preventing re-syncing of old highlights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Image Captioning (Bachelor Thesis)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/automated-image-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/automated-image-captioning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;-colab-notebookhttpscolabresearchgooglecomdrive1q553uslyw3ho6p1g46soedxos_vmhxfj&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1Q553uslYW3Ho6P1G46SOEDxOS_VmHXfJ&#34;&gt;Colab Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this project, I implemented the paper &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1502.03044&#34;&gt;Show, Attend and Tell: Neural Image Caption Generation with Visual Attention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The neural network, a combination of &lt;strong&gt;CNN&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;LSTM&lt;/strong&gt;, was trained on the &lt;strong&gt;MS COCO&lt;/strong&gt; dataset and it learns to generate captions from images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the network generates the caption, word by word, the model’s gaze (attention) shifts across the image. This allows it to focus on those parts of the image which is more relevant for the next word to be generated.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/automated-image-captioning/img1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Attention Mechanism&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Todo List App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/todo-list-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/todo-list-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;-view-apphttpsarkalim-todo-listnetlifyapp&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://arkalim-todo-list.netlify.app&#34;&gt;View App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-githubhttpsgithubcomarkalimtodo-list-app&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arkalim/todo-list-app&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A to-do list web application built using &lt;strong&gt;React&lt;/strong&gt; that allows the user to add, remove and edit their todos. Todo lists are stored in the browser local storage. I built this app while learning &lt;strong&gt;React&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Face Landmarks Detection using CNN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/face-landmarks-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/face-landmarks-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;-colab-notebookhttpscolabresearchgooglecomdrive1tow7w_wu4oltogzfz_0krpxmhdfr2gmb&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1TOw7W_WU4oltoGZfZ_0krpxmhdFR2gmb&#34;&gt;Colab Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-blog-postblogface-landmarks-detection&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;../../blog/face-landmarks-detection&#34;&gt;Blog Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this project, I trained a neural network to localize key points on faces. &lt;strong&gt;Resnet-18&lt;/strong&gt; was used as the model with some slight modifications to the input and output layer. The model was trained on the official &lt;strong&gt;DLib Dataset&lt;/strong&gt; containing &lt;strong&gt;6666 images&lt;/strong&gt; along with corresponding &lt;strong&gt;68-point landmarks&lt;/strong&gt; for each face. Additionally, I wrote a custom data preprocessing pipeline in &lt;strong&gt;PyTorch&lt;/strong&gt; to increase variance in the input images to help the model generalize better. The neural network was trained for 30 epochs before it reached the optima.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaze-tracking Goggles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/gaze-tracking-goggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/gaze-tracking-goggles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project was to build goggles which could find where the user was looking (gaze), the category of object the user was looking at, and the duration of attention on that object. The goggles had 3 camera modules, one on each eye to track the pupil movement and the third one for mapping the gaze to the real world. Thresholding was used to detect the pupils and contours were used to find its centre. Various important parameters such as pupil velocity, acceleration, and fixation time were calculated for further statistical analysis. &lt;strong&gt;Single Shot Descriptor&lt;/strong&gt;, with &lt;strong&gt;VGG16&lt;/strong&gt; as backbone, was used to detect the objects the user was gazing at. Additionally, a GUI was made using &lt;strong&gt;TkInter&lt;/strong&gt; for ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenQuad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/openquad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/openquad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;-githubhttpsgithubcomopenquad-rmiopenquad&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenQuad-RMI/openquad&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project is to build an open-source quadcopter platform for research in the field of drone autonomy. Various deep learning and computer vision algorithms will be implemented on the drone including person tracking, gesture control using human pose estimation, optical flow stabilization, obstacle avoidance, and depth estimation using monocular vision. The drone uses a &lt;strong&gt;Pixhawk&lt;/strong&gt; flight controller with &lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt; as a companion computer. &lt;strong&gt;DJI Flame Wheel-450&lt;/strong&gt; is used for the quadcopter frame along with some custom mountings for adding additional components.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search and Reconnaissance Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/search-and-reconnaissance-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/search-and-reconnaissance-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presented in the 4th International and 19th National Conference on Machine and Mechanisms (&lt;strong&gt;iNaCoMM 2019&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published in the &lt;strong&gt;Springer 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-publicationhttpswwwresearchgatenetpublication343361428_search_and_reconnaissance_robot_for_disaster_management&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/343361428_Search_and_Reconnaissance_Robot_for_Disaster_Management&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natural disasters like earthquakes and landslides are sudden events that cause widespread destruction and major collateral damage including loss of life. Though disasters can never be prevented, their effects on mankind can surely be reduced. In this paper, we present the design and control of SRR (Search and Reconnaissance Robot), a robot capable of traversing on all terrains and locating survivors stuck under the debris. This will assist the rescue team to focus on recovering the victims, leaving the locating task for the Robots. The unique features of the SRR above existing ATVs are active-articulation, modularity, and assisted-autonomy. Active-articulation allows the SRR to climb objects much tall than itself. Modularity allows the SRR to detach into smaller modules to enter tight spaces where the whole body can’t fit. Assisted-autonomy allows the SRR to detect the presence of objects in front and climb autonomously over them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEBART-Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sebart-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sebart-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I worked on this project single-handedly during the summer break following my freshman year at NIT- Trichy. &lt;strong&gt;SEBART-Pro&lt;/strong&gt; is a robot that follows a ball while balancing on two wheels. It can also recognize traffic signs and act accordingly. It has two stepper motors for precise position control and used an &lt;strong&gt;Arduino Nano&lt;/strong&gt; as the microcontroller. The robot senses the tilt using an &lt;strong&gt;MPU-6050 (6-axis gyroscope and accelerometer)&lt;/strong&gt; and converts the values from these sensors into angles using a &lt;strong&gt;Kalman Filter&lt;/strong&gt;. It uses the &lt;strong&gt;PID control algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; to balance on two wheels and a simple &lt;strong&gt;Convolutional Neural Network&lt;/strong&gt; is used to recognize traffic signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
