<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on Maxime Chemin</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on Maxime Chemin</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Search and Reconnaissance Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/search-and-reconnaissance-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/search-and-reconnaissance-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presented in the 4th International and 19th National Conference on Machine and Mechanisms (&lt;strong&gt;iNaCoMM 2019&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published in the &lt;strong&gt;Springer 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-publicationhttpswwwresearchgatenetpublication343361428_search_and_reconnaissance_robot_for_disaster_management&#34;&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/343361428_Search_and_Reconnaissance_Robot_for_Disaster_Management&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natural disasters like earthquakes and landslides are sudden events that cause widespread destruction and major collateral damage including loss of life. Though disasters can never be prevented, their effects on mankind can surely be reduced. In this paper, we present the design and control of SRR (Search and Reconnaissance Robot), a robot capable of traversing on all terrains and locating survivors stuck under the debris. This will assist the rescue team to focus on recovering the victims, leaving the locating task for the Robots. The unique features of the SRR above existing ATVs are active-articulation, modularity, and assisted-autonomy. Active-articulation allows the SRR to climb objects much tall than itself. Modularity allows the SRR to detach into smaller modules to enter tight spaces where the whole body can’t fit. Assisted-autonomy allows the SRR to detect the presence of objects in front and climb autonomously over them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEBART-Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sebart-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sebart-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I worked on this project single-handedly during the summer break following my freshman year at NIT- Trichy. &lt;strong&gt;SEBART-Pro&lt;/strong&gt; is a robot that follows a ball while balancing on two wheels. It can also recognize traffic signs and act accordingly. It has two stepper motors for precise position control and used an &lt;strong&gt;Arduino Nano&lt;/strong&gt; as the microcontroller. The robot senses the tilt using an &lt;strong&gt;MPU-6050 (6-axis gyroscope and accelerometer)&lt;/strong&gt; and converts the values from these sensors into angles using a &lt;strong&gt;Kalman Filter&lt;/strong&gt;. It uses the &lt;strong&gt;PID control algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; to balance on two wheels and a simple &lt;strong&gt;Convolutional Neural Network&lt;/strong&gt; is used to recognize traffic signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
